A Guide to the Hopkins and Bro. (Accomack County, Va.) business records, 1883-1915
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Hopkins and Bro. (Accomack County, Va.) business records, 1883-1915
The Library of Virginia
53421
.9 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Hopkins and Bro.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Nicole and Todd Ballance, Smithfield, Virginia.
Historical Information
Hopkins and Bro. was a merchant firm in Accomack County, Virginia, operated by R. L. Hopkins (1860-1922) and his brother William E. Hopkins (1854-1903) and then his nephew William E. Hopkins (1880-1936). Hopkins and Bro. sold a wide ranges of goods and products from agricultural implements to fertilizer to lumber to shingles. The company also served as agents for the Baltimore, Chesapeake, and Atlantic Railway in Accomack County.
Scope and Content
Business records, 1883-1915, of Hopkins and Bro. of Accomack County, Virginia, consisting of account books, bills of lading, catalogs, circulars, clippings, correspondence, invoices, notes, notices, price lists, receipts, and other documents detailing Hopkins and Bro.'s mercantile business, including as agent for the Baltimore, Chesapeake, and Atlantic Railway.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged
Series I: General business records, 1883, 1894, 1904-1905
Series II: Baltimore, Chesapeake, and Atlantic records, 1907-1915
Contents List
- Series I: General business records, 1883, 1894, 1904-1905, 1883, 1894, 1904-1905., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  Series I: General business records, 1883, 1894, 1904-1905, contains account book, 1894, of R. L. Hopkins (1860-1922); catalogs, circulars, correspondence, invoices, price lists, and other documents, 1883, 1904-1905, from businesses to Hopkins and Bro. regarding commodities, shipment of goods, and payment of bills; correspondence, 1905, of Hopkins and Bro. concerning the purchase of goods; correspondence, 1904-1905, from customers of Hopkins and Bro. regarding the purchase and payment of items; family correspondence, 1905, to R. L. Hopkins from his sister and his cousin; and political correspondence and clippings, 1905, regarding Virginia state politics.
  - R. L. Hopkins account book, 1894. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Companies--A, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Agricultural Chemical Company (Baltimore, MD), 1904-1905. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Companies--B, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Baugh and Sons Company (Baltimore, MD), 1905. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Boyle Manufacturing Company (Martin County, NC), 1905. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Companies--C, 1904-1905. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cockey and Company, Inc. (Baltimore, MD), 1905. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Companies--D, E, F, 1883, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Dennis Simmons Lumber Company (Martin County, NC), 1904-1905. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Companies--G, H, I, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Companies--J-Je, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Companies--Jo, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - John J. Buffington and Company, 1904-1905. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Companies--L, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Lyon, Conklin and Company, 1904-1905. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Companies--M, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Companies--N, O, P, 1904-1905. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Passmore and Gillespie (Chester County, PA), 1905. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Pocomoke Guano Company (Norfolk, VA), 1904-1905. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Companies--R, S, 1904-1905. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Standard Oil Company (Baltimore, MD), 1905. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Companies--T, U, V, W, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Wicomico Brick Company (Salisbury, MD), 1905. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Wm. B. Tilghman Company (Salisbury, MD), 1905. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Hopkins and Bro correspondence, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence--business (customers)--A-E, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence--business (customers)--F-Y, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence--family, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence--political, 1905. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Clippings and miscellaneous papers, 1905, undated. (Box 1, Folder 31)